XML and
xhtml briefly spoke about them
before xhtml is completely defunked you
don't even need to learn about it other
than to know that anybody who's got a
web page with xhtml is probably going to
be able to be hacked so that's it XML is
like this right here this is what XML
looks like it has a it has a header at
the top that tells what kind of XML is
being used it has a mandatory doc type
header which tells what standard is
being used and then it has a number of
elements that have you know SVG in this
case a tag the wct element this is has
this is a self closing tag so it looks a
lot like HTML and xhtml is this really
horrible idea to make another version
HTML 4 which is dead and defunct now
don't use it use HTML 5 uh but it looks
like this so the only time you're ever
going to see XML in modern practice is
in SV GS scalable vector graphics which
are pictures images that have
instructions about how to how to draw
themselves like this right about how to
draw the picture so I did another video
about raster versus uh rasterized raster
images versus um scalable vector
graphics um that's really important that
you understand that you don't have to
get into an El and become a designer or
something but you just need to know what
they are so like a level one knowledge
on a scale of one to 10 10 being you
invented it um and so this is it this is
all you need to know this is what a uh
this is what an image looks like you can
actually animate um a scalable Vector
graphic uh images using XML um and
intermixing JavaScript and all kinds of
fun stuff in there but that's for
another day for somebody else who wants
to do that that's not mandatory as a
beginner you just need to know what XML
is another couple another there's a few
other important things that were written
with XML so um the math standard is XML
but nobody hardly ever uses it they use
math Jacks instead separate video about
that um the Microsoft Word almost all
Microsoft Word documents as far as I
know are XML in the core so there are
some applications that store their files
as XML but it's one of these things
where you'll never read it kind of like
postcript with a PDF you you know it's
there and you know what it is but you
don't necessarily have to deal with it
right you might be one of the people
that having to deal with XML in which
case you know how to get started with it
but that's that's it I needed to at
least make a video to mention it because
somebody's going to ask what about XML
what about
xhtml and dhtml dynamic HTML which is
sort of a riff off of the xhtml kind of
thing just now you know that they these
things exist XML is still relevant it's
still used but it's primarily a file
format for things like word nvg and
stuff like that that so it's it's not
going to be something you're going to
have to probably work with ever unless
you become a specialist that's that's
generating that kind of stuff um for the
record web API is the ability to you
know publish data on the web in data
form that can be consumed by other
applications that is done by Json which
we will be learning in depth and the
ability to have structured data or a ra
or for kubernetes or something like that
in yaml is also really really mandatory
learn
so make sure you don't skip those videos
on Json and yaml doing stuff and and to
a lesser degree toml I'll do a video on
toml I made the logo by the way and but
Json and but Json and and yaml are well
way worth your time more than XML but
now you know what it is